So it's time to continue our journey into the world of open source and understand which models we should
오픈 소스 세계로 여정을 계속하면서 오픈 소스 코드 생성 능력을 조사하기
pick to investigate the ability to generate open source code.
위해 어떤 모델을 선택해야 할지 알아보죠
Where do we begin?
어디서부터 시작하죠?
We begin, of course, with the big code models leaderboard.
우선은 큰 코드 모델의 leaderboard를 보시죠
This is the leaderboard running as a hugging face space that we looked at before, and it's the one
이건 아까 봤던 포옹하는 얼굴 공간으로 실행되는 leaderboard입니다
that compares the performance of open source models in code generation tasks.
코드 생성 작업에서 오픈 소스 모델의 성능을 비교하는 거죠
You remember we started by just looking at base models, and we can see some of the base models that
처음에 베이스모델을 봤을 때 몇몇 베이스모델이 잘 작동하고 있는
are doing really well, including including Code Llama, Code Kwan and Deep Sikh Coder.
것을 볼 수 있습니다 코드 라마, 코드 콴 딥 시크 코더가 있네요
Um, but we're going to look at all models because we're interested in models that have been fine tuned
하지만 모든 모델을 살펴볼 겁니다 미세 조정된 모델에
because they really do perform much, much better than some of the base models when they've been trained
관심이 많거든요 C 플러스 플러스 코드 같은 작업에 맞게 특별히 훈련된
specifically for, uh, for tasks such as C plus plus code.
몇몇 기본 모델보다 훨씬 더 잘 수행하니까요
Um, and we're going to be looking at Python and C plus plus test ability because that is, after all,
그리고 파이썬 + C+ 테스트 기능을 살펴볼 겁니다 왜냐하면 결국 우리가
what we're going to be doing.
할 것이니까요
And when we look at these, one thing to note is that the ones that say exit here, their benchmark,
이걸 볼 때 주목할 점은 여기서 나가라는 건 기준점이 되는 거죠 외부적으로
some of their scoring has happened externally.
채점이 발생했어요
So I'm personally going to tend to lean towards ones that don't have that symbol, that are the ones
그래서 저는 개인적으로 이 기호가 없는 걸 선호합니다
that have been benchmarked as part of the hugging face, uh, spaces platform and the the one that is
안는 얼굴, 스페이스 플랫폼의 벤치마크로 지정된 것들요 그중에서도 가장
top of the list here is code Kwan 1.57 billion, right up at the top.
높은 게 코드 콴 1이죠 570억 달러요, 맨 위에요
The code variant of Kwan.
코드 변종 콴이에요
It's been trained for chat, which means that you can interact with it rather than just, for example,
채팅도 가능하게끔 훈련되어 있습니다 즉, 단순히 파이썬 코드를 주고 완료되기를 기대하는
giving it some Python code and expecting it to complete.
것과는 다른 상호작용이 가능하다는 것이죠
You can have a chat with it, such as saying, hey, could you convert this Python code to highly optimized
채팅을 할 수 있습니다 파이썬 코드를 최적화된 C+로 변환할 수 있나요?
C plus?
그리고요?
Let's go in and have a look.
들어가서 한번 보죠
We're now looking at the code Kwan 1.57 billion chat the top model.
지금 보시는 건 코드 콴 1이에요 570억 챗의 톱모델이죠
And you can see here it describes some of what it can do.
여기 보시면 이게 뭘 할 수 있는지 설명돼 있죠
Um and some of how you can interact with it.
어떻게 상호 작용할 수 있는지도요
Like you can say, write a quicksort algorithm in Python.
파이썬 에서 퀵 센서트 알고리즘을 작성하세요
Um, and you can see that you can construct messages in much the way that we are used to, and then
보시다시피 우리가 쓰던 방식으로 메시지를 만들 수 있어요 토큰라이저 앱으로
use the tokenizer apply chat template to convert that in tokens and run that through the model.
채팅 템플릿을 적용하면 메시지를 토큰으로 변환하고 모델로 실행할 수 있죠
So this is all very consistent with the way that we ran a number of models for other simple activities,
과거 간단한 작업, 텍스트 생성 작업을 위해 실행했던 여러 모델과
text generation activities in the past.
아주 일관된 방식이죠
If we look at Codeclan we can see that it scores really very well indeed in Python coding and in C plus
Codeclan을 보시면 파이썬 코딩에서 C++ 코딩에서 아주 높은 점수를 얻을 수
plus coding.
있어요
It is only beaten by this one here, which is the externally run one which only fractionally does better.
외부 실행 장치인 이것에 의해만 패하고 있어요 이건 아주 조금 더 잘 작동하죠
And if you look, this model itself is in fact a fine tune of Quinn itself.
잘 보면 이 모델 자체가 퀸의 훌륭한 곡조예요
So I think frankly, we're doing pretty well by sticking with code.
솔직히 코드를 고수하면서 잘 되고 있다고 생각해요
Quinn.
퀸이에요
There's a big drop off after that.
그 뒤엔 급경사면이 있어요
The other one that I was interested in showing you was I wanted to also show you Code Gemma down here,
또 보여드리고 싶은 건 코드 젬마도 보여드리고 싶어요 다른
which I thought would be great to try a different one and see Google.
것도 해보고 구글도 보죠
But as it happens, when I try to use code.
하지만 코드를 사용하려 할 때 발생하는 일이죠
Gemma uh, it was able to to answer very simple tasks, but it crashed whenever it was given harder
제마는 아주 간단한 임무에 대처할 수 있었지만 어려운 임무를 받을 때마다 고장 났어요
You may want to try and see as an exercise whether you can get code.
코드를 얻을 수 있는지 훈련으로 알아보세요.
Gemma to work, but I wasn't able to for this particular problem, at least not for any complicated,
하지만 이 문제 때문에 작업을 할 수가 없었어요. 적어도 C 플러스 버전의 파이썬의
uh, translation or reimplementation of Python in C plus plus.
복잡한 번역이나 재공여가 일어나지 않았기 때문이죠.
But certainly an exercise for you will be to try out other models, because we have so many to choose
하지만 다른 모델도 시도해 보는 것도 분명 도움이 될 거예요
from and see what you find.
선택지가 아주 많거든요
So we've picked, uh, Code Quan.
코드 콴을 선택했어요
Let's go into it one more time.
한 번 더 얘기해 보죠
Uh, the next thing to do is to figure out, okay, how are we going to run this various ways?
다음으로 할 일은 다양한 방식으로 어떻게 실행할지 알아내는 거죠
We could do it.
할 수 있어요
You already know of one of them.
한 명은 이미 알고 계시잖아요
We could go onto Google Colab and write the code to use the Hugging Face Transformers library to directly
구글 Colab으로 가서 코드를 작성할 수 있습니다 안기 트랜스포머 라이브러리를
access Codex code, load it in and run it in inference time.
이용해 코덱스 코드에 직접 접근해 로드하고 추론 시간에 실행하는 거죠
And that would work great.
그럼 아주 좋을 거예요
The thing is, I want to execute the compiled code on my box, so it would be a bit inconvenient.
비트 박스에서 컴파일된 코드를 실행하고 싶다면 약간 불편할 거예요
We'd have to run that in Jupyter, in in Google Colab, and then copy and paste the code over to my
주피터에서 실행해야 합니다 구글 Colab에서요 제 컴퓨터에 코드를 복사 붙여넣기
box.
하죠
And I was hoping to be able to do it all in one nice user interface.
하나의 사용자 인터페이스로 다 할 수 있길 바랐어요
And so basically I want to be able to run this model as it is, but from my box.
기본적으로 이 모델을 있는 그대로 실행하고 싶어요 제 상자에서요
Now there are a few ways of doing that, and I'm not going to go into all of them, but there's one
그렇게 할 방법이 몇 가지 있는데 전부 설명하진 않겠지만 아주
that's super convenient, and it's actually going to show us a way that you can deploy models in production
편리한 방법이 있어요 프로덕션에서 모델을 배포하는 방법을 보여드릴 겁니다 프로덕션
for production purposes.
목적을 위해서요
And that is to ask hugging face to run this model for you and to give you an endpoint which you can
페이스 포옹에 이 모델을 실행해 달라고 요청하는 겁니다 여러분이 코드에서 원격으로 모델을
use to call the model remotely from your code.
호출할 수 있는 엔드포인트를 주는 거죠
So it's a sort of hosting solution for running a model like this model, or any open source model you
이런 모델이나 여러분이 원하는 오픈 소스 모델을 실행하는 일종의 호스팅 솔루션으로 여러분이
want, and give you an endpoint to run it yourself.
실행할 수 있는 엔드포인트를 제공하죠
And that sounds super advanced.
정말 고급 기술 같네요
You may think that there's going to be a lot to it to do this.
할 일이 많을 거라고 생각할 수도 있어요
It turns out it's not difficult at all.
전혀 어렵지 않아요
All you have to do is go to this deploy button right here.
여러분이 할 일은 여기 이 배포 버튼으로 가는 것뿐이에요
And the first option here is inference endpoints dedicated inference deployments for production.
첫 번째 옵션은 종점 추론입니다 프로덕션에 대한 전용 추론 배포죠
And it's saying this is a way you can have your own deployment of this model.
이 모델의 고유한 배포를 가질 수 있는 방법이라고 하네요
And you'll be able to call it yourself from anywhere and use this model on your own.
어디서든 직접 호출해 이 모델을 사용할 수 있어요
Now of course you'll have to pay for that.
물론 그 대가를 치러야겠죠
It doesn't come for free, but it's not massively expensive.
공짜는 아니지만 아주 비싸진 않아요
But this is one that is, it costs a little bit more.
하지만 이건 비트가 좀 더 비싸요
It's something certainly to be aware of.
확실히 알아야 할 일이죠
Um, so when you, when you come in to, to use one of these inference endpoints, you choose whether
이런 추론 끝점을 사용할 때 AWS나 애저 GCP, 구글
you want to run on AWS or Azure or GCP, Google Cloud.
클라우드에서 실행할지 선택해요
And you can also choose whether you want a CPU box or a GPU box.
CPU 박스와 GPU 박스도 선택할 수 있어요
In the case of this model, we would need to have a GPU box, and we would need to have at least an
이 모델의 경우 GPU 박스가 필요하고 엔비디아 L4도 최소한 있어야
Nvidia L4.
해요
At least that is what it is recommending to us, which has 24GB of Ram on the GPU.
적어도 그게 권장하는 거죠 GPU 상에 24GB 램이 있어요
Uh, so we'd simply select this and then we would go ahead and, uh, fill in some of these things and
그래서 이걸 선택하고 이 중 몇 개를 채우고 엔드포인트 생성을
click Create Endpoint.
클릭해요
And it's as easy as that.
아주 간단해요
We would have our own dedicated endpoint for for your personal use running with hugging face paying
전용 엔드포인트를 만들어서 당신을 위해 0달러 내고 얼굴 껴안고 달리게 할
$0.80 an hour.
거예요 시간당 80달러요
If you're in the US, you may see different pricing there.
미국에서는 가격이 다를 수 있어요
So you know it's not super cheap, but you can turn it off and on whenever you want.
아주 저렴하진 않지만 원할 때 껐다 켤 수 있어요
So for doing an experiment, if this is just going to take you an hour or two, uh, it's something
실험에 한두 시간밖에 안 걸린다면 정말 재미있는
that's that's great fun to do, I recommend it, uh, if your budget allows for these things, but if
실험이 될 거예요 예산에 맞는다면 추천합니다 그렇지 않다면 걱정 마세요
not, never fear, I've done it for you.
제가 해드릴게요
You can watch along and see what it's like.
여러분도 함께 지켜보며 어떤지 보세요
I'm going to go to my dedicated endpoints using this menu right here.
여기 이 메뉴를 이용해 지정된 끝점으로 가보죠
And you'll see that I've got two dedicated endpoints that I've set up.
지정된 끝점이 2개 있는 게 보이시죠 제가 설정한 거요
One of them is indeed Codeclan, the one we've just been looking at.
그중 하나가 방금 본 코드클란이에요
I basically followed through that screen and it's running on that box that was recommended, the L four.
기본적으로 저 화면을 따라가면 추천받은 L4 상자에서 실행되고 있어요
So I am currently spending $0.80 an hour for the pleasure of running this endpoint.
현재 0달러 썼어요 시간당 80달러로 이 엔드포인트를 운영하는 기쁨을 누리세요
Don't let it be said I don't do anything for you.
내가 당신을 위해 아무것도 안 한다는 말은 하지 말아요
And I also, as I say, I tried code Gemma.
코드 젬마도 시도해 봤어요
I tried it on an alpha box.
알파 박스에 써봤어요
I was not able to get this to run.
Get it을 실행할 수가 없었어요
It would do simple, simple stuff, but anything too complicated it would crash.
아주 단순한 작업이지만 너무 복잡하면 충돌해요
But I love this to be an exercise for you to come in and try this.
하지만 이걸 연습 삼아 한번 해 보세요
Try getting code Gemma to work, and then I'd be interested to see how it matches up with code.
코드 제마를 작동시켜 보세요 코드랑 어떻게 일치하는지 보고 싶네요
But I think you'll find that just as we saw from the leaderboard, there will be very little doubt that
하지만 리더보드에서 본 것처럼 의심의 여지가 없어요
Codeclan is hugely superior and very, very capable of these kinds of tasks.
코드클란이 훨씬 뛰어나고 이런 장애물을 잘 해낼 거예요
So at this point, you have hopefully followed this through.
지금까지는 잘 따라오셨길 바라요
You have to wait five minutes, go and get a coffee for for the codeclan endpoint to come up and running,
5분 기다렸다가 커피를 마시고 codeclan 엔드포인트가 실행될 때까지
and then we'll be ready to get back to JupyterLab running on our box to call this endpoint and to try
기다리세요 그런 다음 JupyterLab으로 돌아가 이 엔드포인트를 호출하고 코드 생성을 시험해볼
out some code generation.
준비가 될 거예요
I will see you in a minute.
잠시 후에 뵙죠